人人影視傾情奉獻
翻譯  草草
時間軸  Ans
顧問  老杜
后期  餓得慌
校對  草草
總監  草草
紙牌屋
第四季  第二集
他是個沒有格調  沒有風度  沒有羞恥的蠻人
He is a classless, graceless, shameless barbarian.
他那么對你  伊麗莎白  簡直惡心
What he did to you, Elizabeth, it was disgusting.
-可怕  -太過分了
- Awful. - Just vile.
-能遞給我那盤...  -好
- Can you pass the plate of... - Yeah.
可你為什么沒告訴我們
But why didn't you tell us?
一想到那么多年來  你一個人抵抗病魔
The thought of you fighting this alone, all those years...
我不希望人可憐
I didn't want pity.
他們真的吵架了嗎
Is it true that they were arguing?
不  她是南下來陪我的
No, she came down here to be with me.
當然  我們沒想到
Of course, we didn't expect
這事會被當眾說出去
that it was gonna be made a public display.
他大概覺得那樣最能打消傳言吧
I guess he thought that was the best way to dispel the rumors.
那人不配當總統
That man does not deserve to be president.
我一向不愿說他壞話  伊麗莎白
I've never wanted to speak ill of him, Elizabeth,
但我一想到他是怎么對待你和克萊爾的
but when I think of the way he's treated you and Claire...
行了  他還是她的女婿呢
Oh, stop now. He is still her son-in-law.
不  芭說得對
No, Bar's right.
他不配當總統
He doesn't deserve to be president.
你們...其實都可以幫我
You could... all help me, actually.
-什么都行  -隨你說
- Anything. - Just say the word.
希瑟·鄧巴
Heather Dunbar.
我們該支持她
We should be supporting her.
用我們的支票支持
With our checkbooks.
你真心希望他輸嗎
You really want him to lose?
等他輸了  克萊爾就能開啟自己的事業了
When he loses, Claire can begin her own career...
這對我來說更加重要
which is far more important to me.
我不知道我們是不是能起到作用  但是
I don't know if we can really make a difference, but...
我想做點比坐在這兒說他壞話更實際的事
I'd rather do more than just sit around and bad-mouth him.
那么  我們就寫張支票嗎
So, we just write a check?
不能讓弗蘭西斯知道
Now, Francis can't know.
我們的捐助得...曲線救國
I mean, our donations will have to be... once removed.
那項修正案已經拖延多年了
That amendment has stalled for years.
因為我們在退休軍人事務處沒人
Because we didn't have someone in Veterans Affairs.
這不是退休軍人問題  是公共衛生問題
It isn't a veterans issue. It's public health.
這不是我的強項
That's not my specialty.
等等  你是說
Wait, you're telling me
你不認識任何得過乳腺癌的人嗎
you don't know anyone who's had breast cancer?
我是指立法方面
I mean in terms of legislation.
多50%
Fifty percent more.
黑人女性患乳腺癌后
That's how many more black women
死亡率比白人女性高50%
die of breast cancer than white women.
在我們選區  比率高于謀殺率
In our district, it's higher than the murder rate.
幫我們拿下診所
Help us get this clinic.
我并不否認這一問題的重要性
I don't deny that it's an important issue,
但我得選好自己支持什么
but I have to pick and choose what I support.
你在家鄉的競選選情嚴峻  議員女士
You're in a tight race back home, Congresswoman.
我們可以建立超級政治行動委員會
We'll set up a super PAC.
三百萬美元
Three million dollars.
你沒跟我談就這么做了
You did this without talking to me?
克萊爾和我好好談過了  母親
Claire and I spoke at length, Mother.
克萊爾
Claire?
你對第一夫人都直呼其名了啊
You're calling the First Lady by her given name, now?
希望你也可以如此  議員女士
Well, and I would hope you would, too, Congresswoman.
你背著我行動  安德伍德夫人
You went behind my back, Mrs. Underwood.
我不是求你全力支持我
I'm not asking for a full endorsement.
我只是求你允許西莉婭延遲競選
I'm just asking for your blessing on Celia delaying her run.
當然  也保證不會跟我競爭
And of course, a promise to not campaign against me.
杰姬·夏普很支持鄧巴
Jackie Sharp's big on Dunbar.
她為什么要幫你
Why would she help you?
這筆錢跟我們不直接掛鉤
This money isn't directly linked to us.
你是說總統樂意
You mean the president's comfortable
給杰姬送競選經費嗎
putting money in Jackie's war chest?
是的  但我們得保密
He is, but we have to keep this quiet.
你們兩個辦公室之間絕對不能有聯絡
There can't be any communication between your office and his.
-講話  -賽斯把最新的改動加進去了
- Speech? - Seth put in your latest edits.
等您批準了  我們就拿給提詞器的人
Once you approve, we'll send it to the teleprompters.
-她到了嗎  -幾分鐘前剛到
- Has she arrived yet? - A few minutes ago.
請坐
Please sit down.
如果杰姬退縮  我們不能給她留后路
If Jackie gets cold feet, we can't leave her any choice.
我已經在處理了
I'm already on top of that.
怎么處理
How?
他們總去同一家酒店
They always use the same hotel.
我找人在街對面守著了
I've got a guy set up across the street.
你會小心行事吧
I'm assuming you're being careful.
我不是單純的技術員  我也會老法子
I'm not just a tech outfit. I can go old school, too.
女士  我們為您備好了午餐
Ma'am? We have lunch prepared for you.
真是氣派
This is impressive.
趁現在好好瞻仰一下吧  我們一會兒就走
Well, soak it up while you can. We won't be here long.
我就回來
I'll be right back.
今晚戴我母親的耳環
歡迎回來
弗蘭西斯
阿納托利·羅斯卓波夫  他的帝國價值300億
Anatoly Rostropov. His empire's worth 30 billion.
佩特羅夫昨晚叫人殺了他
Petrov had him killed last night.
史坦尼斯拉夫·烏斯特拉維奇
Stanislav Ustravich,
特卡斯石油的創始人
founder of Turkas Oil.
今早早些時候被發現身亡
Found dead early this morning.
伊戈爾·米爾金  媒體大亨  身價240億
Igor Milkin, media tycoon worth 24 billion.
被政府沒收了
Very outspoken against Petrov
電視臺和報社后一直公開抨擊佩特羅夫
after the government seized his TV stations and newspapers.
兩小時前  他的私人飛機在緬因州班格爾降落
His private plane landed in Bangor, Maine, two hours ago.
我們在停機坪上隔離了他
We've got him quarantined on the tarmac.
他尋求政治庇護  說擔心自己有生命危險
He's seeking political asylum. Says he's in fear for his life.
我們認為他們一直在密謀推翻佩特羅夫
We believe they've been formulating a plan to unseat Petrov.
布魯特斯  卡西烏斯  還有那個逃脫的家伙[刺殺凱撒]
Brutus, Cassius, and the one that got away.
莫斯科堅決要我們馬上把他送回去
Moscow's adamant we send him back immediately.
那就送他回去
Then send him back.
我不希望國情咨文被
I don't want the State of the Union
庇護糾紛蓋過風頭
overshadowed by some asylum dispute.
他是佩特羅夫的麻煩  不關我們的事
He's Petrov's problem, not ours.
從法律上講  先生
Legally, sir,
我們有義務處理他的庇護請求
we are obligated to process his asylum request.
-媒體不是已經知道了吧  -不  先生
- Don't tell me the press knows he's here. - No, sir.
他們一進入美國領空
We jammed communications on his plane
我們就屏蔽了他飛機的通訊
as soon as it entered U.S. airspace.
那不就沒有問題了嗎
Then we don't have a problem, do we?
如果我們送他回去  他很可能會被殺
It's likely he'll be killed if we send him back.
那又如何  他想屠龍  又沒打中
So be it. He tried to slay a dragon and he missed the mark.
現在他得面對怒火了
Now he's gotta face the fire.
我們擔心會發生更多殺戮  更多公司被查抄
Our fear is more killings, more company seizures.
會導致銀行擠兌
That leads to a run on the banks,
盧布崩潰  債務違約
collapse of the ruble, default on debts.
我們已經知道
And we already know
他一直在跟國際貨幣基金組織暗中聯絡
he's been back-channeling about a bailout
討論救市計劃
with the IMF.
你如果有提議  就快點說
Well, if you have a proposal to make, then make it quickly.
-我還得準備講話呢  -是  先生
- I have a speech to prep for. - Yes, sir.
去年您穿的是灰褐色  或許這件太像了
Last year you wore the taupe, so maybe this is too similar?
請進
Come in.
我接通了黑爾太太的電話
I was able to get Mrs. Hale on the phone.
太好了  能讓我們單獨待會兒嗎
Oh, great. Uh, could you excuse me for a moment?
-母親  -您沒事吧  黑爾太太
- Mother? - You doing okay, Mrs. Hale?
是的  謝謝
Yes, thank you.
那是誰
Who was that?
我獎勵自己做美甲呢
I'm treating myself to a pedicure.
沒人能聽到我
Nobody can hear me.
你想談談嗎
You wanted to talk?
是的  我想感謝你  感謝你的幫助
Yes, I wanted to thank you, for all of your help.
看來議員女士傾向于同意了
Uh, it looks like the congresswoman is leaning toward a yes.
我在想  等你競選時
You know, I was thinking, when you run,
你該用你的娘家姓
you should use your maiden name instead.
母親  我不能那么做  面子上過不去
Mother, I couldn't do that. It would look bad.
那可不可以...
Well, then how about if you...
叫克萊爾·黑爾-安德伍德
if you use Claire Hale-Underwood?
這聽上去挺不錯的
That has a nice ring to it.
或許吧
Maybe.
-你見他了嗎  -還沒
- Have you seen him yet? - No, not yet.
你今晚打算穿什么
What are you gonna wear tonight?
其實我正在考慮呢
I was just deciding that now, actually.
希望是件深色的
Something dark, I hope.
要么是黑色  要么是象牙白  老實說
Well, it's between black and ivory, and to tell you the truth,
象牙白這件美極了
this ivory is so beautiful--
老天爺  別穿象牙白
Oh, for God's sakes, don't wear ivory.
就算是你那樣的身材
Even with your figure,
也只會突出各種不該突出的地方
it'll accentuate all the wrong places.
你會看講話嗎
Are you going to watch the speech?
母親
Mother?
嗯  我...
Yes, I'm gonna...
我會讓邁克爾在臥室里擺臺電視
I'm gonna have Michael put a TV in the bedroom.
安德伍德夫人  總統在等您了
Mrs. Underwood, the president is ready for you.
我就出去
I'll be right out.
母親  我得掛了
Mother, I have to go.
嗯  當然  你肯定很忙
Yes, I-- Of course. I'm sure you must be very busy.
回家見
I'll see you when I get home?
如果我睡了
If I'm asleep...
那我們早上見
Then I'll see you in the morning.
再見  母親
Goodbye, Mother.
再見  穿黑的那件
Bye. Wear the black!
這事絕不能泄露出去
I don't want even the slightest chance this gets out.
我們設了警戒線  機尾號也會遮住
We set up a perimeter. And we'll cover the tail number.
很好  跟佩特羅夫約好講話后通話
Good. Set up a call with Petrov, for after the speech.
那時莫斯科是凌晨五點
It'll be 5:00 a.m. in Moscow.
他肯定會看的
Oh, I guarantee he'll be watching.
先生  您得接一下
Sir? I think you should take this.
失陪
Excuse me.
你好  議員女士
Hello, Congresswoman.
抱歉來晚了  請坐
Sorry for the delay. Please sit down.
你收到耳環了嗎
Did you get the earrings?
是的  謝謝
I did. Thank you.
我母親的  兩克拉鉆石
My mother's. Two-carat diamonds.
今晚戴吧
For tonight.
沒什么比得上鉆石耳環了
There's nothing quite like diamond earrings.
我們開始吧
Shall we begin?
今年  我們要改變一下出場方式
Uh, this year, we're handling the arrival a bit differently.
您將先被護送去圓形大廳與領導層合影
You'll be escorted to the rotunda for a photo op with the leadership
然后再去等候室
before going to the holding room.
我不需要去等候室
I don't need to go to the holding room.
你直接帶我去大廳吧
You can take me directly to the gallery.
沒關系  都聽第一夫人的
Yes, that's fine. Whatever the First Lady prefers.
之后我們需要分兩個車隊
And we'll need two separate motorcades after.
我要直接去機場
I'll be going straight to the airport.
-那就兩個車隊  -是  先生
- Two motorcades, then. - Yes, sir.
我想向你們匯報一下特別來賓名單
I'd like to brief you on the list of special guests attending--
看上去沒什么問題
This all seems pretty straightforward.
如果你覺得沒問題我也沒問題
I'm good if you are.
嗯  沒問題  多謝你了
Yes, I'm fine. Thank you so very much.
你有空嗎
Do you have a moment?
伊麗莎白怎么樣了
How's Elizabeth?
她讓我代她問好
She sends her regards.
當然了
I'll bet she does.
競選呢
And the campaign?
還在試探
Still exploring viability.
桃瑞絲還沒答應嗎
Doris isn't on board yet?
回頭就知道了
Uh, we'll see.
你給了她什么
What have you offered her?
我想先跟莉安策劃一個穩妥的競選策略
Well, I want to put together a solid campaign strategy with LeAnn
再跟她二次接觸
before engaging her again.
如果你需要我幫忙  就告訴我
Well, if you need my help, let me know.
我當黨鞭時  我們關系很好
She and I were very close when I was whip.
-你的事夠多了  -不麻煩的
- You've got a lot on your plate. - No, it's no trouble at all.
我再找你吧
I'll let you know.
今晚見
See you tonight.
可以開始準備了嗎  先生
You ready to prep, sir?
我要做些改動
I need to make some changes.
我去叫講稿撰寫人
I'll call the speech writers.
不用  我自己來  去把克麗絲塔找來
No, I wanna do these myself. And track down Calista.
我們還得再加一名賓客
We have to make room for one more guest.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
怎么回事
What's that?
我要把文身洗掉
I'm having it removed.
太可惜了  我挺喜歡呢
Well, that's too bad. I liked it.
該向前看了
Hmm, time to move on.
你想放下什么
From what?
需要文身的我
From the me that needed a tattoo.
我沒多少時間
I don't have much time.
你什么時候得去國會大廈
When do you have to be at the Capitol?
不到一小時后
Less than an hour.
-威士忌還是伏特加  -伏特加
- Whiskey or vodka? - Vodka.
你對桃瑞絲·瓊斯有多了解
How well do you know Doris Jones?
見過她幾次  不怎么了解
Oh, uh, met her a few times. I don't know her that well, though.
-怎么  -她女兒  西莉婭
- Why? - Her daughter, Celia,
希望我幫他們弄到撥款
wants me to help them get appropriations
籌建一家乳腺癌診所
for a breast cancer clinic.
作為回報  他們愿用德州的錢資助我的競選
In return, they want to pad my campaign with Texas money.
-多少  -三百萬
- How much? - Three million.
可能還不止
To start.
她的選區才沒那么多錢
Her district doesn't have that kind of money.
西莉婭說他們的捐助人是30區以外的
Celia says they're courting donors from outside the 30th.
但我一個助手
But one of my aides
聽說克萊爾·安德伍德和莉安·哈維
heard that Claire Underwood and LeAnn Harvey
今天去了瓊斯的辦公室
were in Jones' office today.
莉安我認識
LeAnn's someone I know.
格蘭頓-希爾幾年前想把她挖來
Glendon Hill was courting her a few years ago.
她拒絕了你嗎
Did she turn you down?
我們請不起她
We couldn't afford her.
我知道你已經金盆洗手了  但這筆錢不是小數
Look, I know you're out of the game, but this is a lot of money.
如果是真  能幫我大忙  如果不是...
If it's legit, it could really help me. But if it's not, I--
我去跟莉安談談  看能問出什么來
I'll talk to LeAnn and see what I can find out.
給
Here.
我想先嘗你
I want to taste you first.
下面是特別報道
This is a special report.
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德總統向國會聯席會議
President Francis Underwood's State of the Union address
發表國情咨文講話
to a joint session of Congress.
今晚  世界的眼睛都盯著華盛頓
Tonight the eyes of the world are on Washington.
安德伍德總統幾分鐘后就將上臺
President Underwood will take the stage in just a few minutes...
把食物拿走
Take the food away.
您午飯就沒吃  黑爾太太
You didn't eat your lunch, Mrs. Hale.
我不舒服
Yeah, well, I didn't feel well.
那您就更該吃點晚飯了  您的藥
Then you really should eat dinner. Your medication--
別讓我再說一遍了  邁克爾
Please don't make me ask you again, Michael.
拿走  這味兒熏得我難受
Just take it away. The smell of it is making me ill.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
女士們先生們  美國第一夫人
Ladies and gentlemen, the First Lady of the United States.
-西莉婭  -謝謝你的安排
- Celia. - Thank you so much for arranging this.
能坐在你旁邊太榮幸了
It's a big honor to be sitting next to you.
議長先生  有請美國總統
Mr. Speaker, the President of the United States.
在這里看國情咨文真有意思
Interesting place to watch the SOTU.
這樣更好玩  跟人民大眾在一起
It's more fun this way. You know, hanging with the hoi polloi.
你為什么來華府
So, what brings you to D.C.?
國會都到齊了  適合攬活兒干
Well, all of Congress in town, it's good for hustling work.
你什么時候攬過活兒  你從來都是拒絕別人
Since when do you hustle? You turn people away.
你怎么知道我在這兒
How'd you know I was in town?
我雖然退休了  但還是眼觀六路耳聽八方
I might be retired, but I still have my ear to the ground.
是真的嘍  偉大的雷米·丹頓解甲歸田了
So that's true? The great Remy Danton has hung up his jersey?
我從未這么痛快過
I've never felt better.
-你不是來跟我寒暄的吧  -不是
- Don't tell me this is a social visit. - No.
-如果不是為公事  -是公事
- Well, if it isn't business... - It's business.
-各位國會議員  -好吧
- Members of Congress... - Okay.
-我十分榮幸  -那么
- ...I have the high privilege... - So...
-等等  節目開始了  -為各位請出
- Oh, hold on. The show is starting. - ...of presenting to you,
美國總統
the President of the United States.
謝謝
Thank you.
非常感謝
Thank you so much.
謝謝  議長先生  副總統先生
Thank you. Mr. Speaker, Mr. Vice President,
各位國會議員  我的美國同胞們
members of Congress, my fellow Americans.
一年前
One year ago,
我第一次做這番講話
when I gave this address for the first time,
當時我國處于完全不同的一個時期
it was during a very different period for our country.
我國正在從一起政治丑聞和
Our nation was recovering from a political scandal
與中國的貿易危機中走出來
and a trade crisis with China.
而你們面前的  是一位未經過選舉的總統
Before you stood a president no one had elected.
但現在  那個人依然站在你們面前
But that same man stands before you now,
而黑暗時期已經過去
and the darkness is behind us.
國家現在情勢大好  前途愈發光明
The state of the union is bright, and getting brighter.
我們遭遇過挑戰  沒錯
We've had our challenges, yes.
尤其是跟俄羅斯
Particularly with Russia.
的確有些很緊張的時刻
There were some tense moments, to be sure,
但我們還是克服了那些緊張
and yet we overcame those tensions.
佩特羅夫總統讓我們繼續建立信任
President Petrov let us continue to build trust
并表現出我們已從去年的經歷中吸取了教訓
and show that we've learned from our experiences last year.
我個人想感謝第一夫人
And I'd personally like to acknowledge the First Lady,
她為修復兩國關系帶了路
who led the way in repairing those burned bridges.
她得到的掌聲比總統還多
She's getting more applause than the president.
對你是好事吧
Good for you, isn't it?
好厲害的客戶
Quite a high-profile client.
誰告訴你的
Who told you that?
只是一猜
Just a guess.
不  你猜錯了
No, you guessed wrong.
你知道有財大氣粗的德州捐助人
So what do you know about big Texas donors...
就為了達拉斯一個窮選區
who care enough about a poor Dallas district
會給加州的競選捐錢嗎
to donate money to a campaign in California?
我沒聽說過
That went right over my head.
第一夫人去了達拉斯  你當時也在那兒
First Lady was in Dallas. You were in Dallas.
第一夫人來了這兒
The First Lady is here.
你也來了
Now you're here.
我覺得你是太閑了  雷米
I think you have far too much time on your hands, Remy.
這筆錢上到處是你的痕跡
Your fingerprints are all over this money.
你現在為杰姬·夏普工作了
You're working for Jackie Sharp now?
不  只是朋友
No. Just friends.
-只是朋友嗎  -嗯
- Just friends, huh? - Yeah.
我覺得她身上也到處是你的痕跡
I think your fingerprints are all over her.
這樣如何
How about this?
你別來刺探我的事
You don't poke around in my shit...
我就不去刺探你的
and I won't poke around in yours.
見到你很高興  雷米  別退休就變慫了
It was good to see you, Remy. Don't get too soft in retirement.
一般來說
Now, it's considered uncouth
正在進行競選的總統
for a president who's in the midst of a campaign,
不該直接談論即將到來的競選  但今晚
to talk directly about the upcoming election, but tonight,
我覺得我必須談
I feel compelled.
因為我們選民即將在
Because the votes our electorate casts
目前的初選和11月的大選中投的票
during the current primaries and the general election in November
將對在座的各位有深遠的影響
will have a profound impact on everyone in this room.
有些人  包括我  可能將失業
Some of us, myself included, may find ourselves out of a job.
如果我們想保住工作
If we want to keep our jobs,
我們就得聆聽美國民眾的聲音
we have to listen to the American people.
我們就得更加努力  說到做到
We have to work harder! We have to deliver!
就像桃瑞絲·瓊斯
Just like Doris Jones.
她已經在國會任職了34年
She has kept her job in Congress for 34 years
因為她從未向逆境低過頭
because she never relented in the face of adversity.
事實上  就在今天  她還為一家她已經爭取了
In fact, just today, she called me about a breast cancer clinic
十年的乳腺癌診所給我打了電話
she has been fighting for over the past decade.
她的計劃很大膽
Now, her plan is bold.
將退伍軍人醫院擴張  向普通民眾開放
A VA hospital expansion open to the general public,
由聯邦資金資助
financed by federal money.
這一大膽計劃能通過科普  篩查
A bold plan that will significantly increase successful diagnoses
和可負擔醫保  大幅提升確診和治療的成功率
and treatment through education, screenings, and affordable care.
她一次次遭遇阻力
Now, she's gotten resistance, time and again...
來自退伍軍人事務處的阻力
from the Veterans Affairs administration,
來自她國會同事的阻力
from her colleagues in Congress...
-能調大聲點嗎  -來自那些不希望
- Can you turn it up a bit? - ...from those who don't want to see
政府給計劃生育組織撥款的人
government funds going to Planned Parenthood.
但是  她今天打給我時
And yet, when she called me today,
她對建立這家診所的熱忱
she was just as passionate about this clinic
一如十年前她第一次跟我提出時那般
as she was when she first brought it up to me ten years ago.
桃瑞絲  你成功了
Well, Doris, it worked.
我會跟退伍軍人事務部長
I'll be working with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs,
住房和城市發展部以及國會領袖合作幫你建立診所
HUD and the congressional leaders to get you that clinic.
因為你  我們將拯救生命
Because of you, we'll save lives.
這正是美國人民想看到的領導
And that is exactly the sort of leadership the American people want.
更多桃瑞絲·瓊斯這樣的領導人
More leaders like Doris Jones.
等她本屆任期結束退休時
And when she retires at the end of this term,
我很高興她女兒西莉婭
I'm delighted to say that her daughter, Celia,
將競選缺職
will run for the open seat
像她母親那樣  繼續實現人民的愿望
to continue delivering just like her mother has.
不會吧
No fucking way.
我本人會
And I, for one, will support
2016國情咨文
百分百支持你的競選
your candidacy with everything I've got.
我知道克萊爾也會的
And I know Claire will, as well.
德州人百折不撓
Texans are tenacious.
我很驕傲我娶了一位
I'm proud to be married to one,
我很驕傲曾與瓊斯議員女士
and I'm proud to have served with one,
這樣的德州人共事過
like Congresswoman Jones.
謝謝你  桃瑞絲  謝謝你多年的服務
Thank you, Doris, for all your years of service,
也謝謝你  西莉婭  繼承母親的衣缽
and thank you, Celia, for picking up the mantle.
桃瑞絲說是她女兒說話冒失
Doris said her daughter spoke out of turn,
她對她和安德伍德協商的交易并不知情
that she didn't know about the deal she was brokering with Underwood.
你跟莉安聯絡上了嗎
Did you connect with LeAnn?
沒有
No, I didn't.
她說她得明天才能見我
She said she couldn't meet until tomorrow.
現在也沒必要了
Well, I guess there's no point now, anyway.
如果是白宮在準備籌款
If the White House is orchestrating the funding,
安德伍德肯定不需要我幫忙
Underwood's not gonna want my help.
該死  那筆錢本來能幫大忙的
Fuck! I really could've used that money.
如果看上去像天上掉餡餅
Well, when it looks too good to be true...
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
我什么時候能再見你
When am I gonna see you again?
我不知道
I don't know.
我有點...悶得發瘋
I've been... feeling a bit stir-crazy.
如果我退休了  或許該出去走走
If I'm retired, I should probably travel some.
你可以去加州啊
Well, you could travel to California.
11月之前  我會更多待在那邊
I'll be there more than here until November.
或許吧
Yeah, maybe.
不去也行
Or don't.
你知道怎么聯系我
You know how to reach me.
你覺得是雷米嗎
Do you think it was Remy?
不太可能  我讓他知道我們知道了
Highly doubtful. I made it clear what we knew.
他知道你有證據嗎
He knows you have proof?
他知道我知道  不知道我有證據
He knows that I know. Not that I have proof.
或許我們不該這就把那張牌打出去
Maybe we shouldn't have played that card yet.
雷米把事情都串起來了
Remy was connecting the dots.
我必須讓他打住
I needed to put the brakes on him.
如果不是他
Well, if it wasn't him,
那肯定是桃瑞絲自己去找了弗蘭西斯
Doris must've gone to Francis himself.
她看到了機會就...
She saw an opening and--
女士  計劃有變
Ma'am, there's been a change of plans.
等等  什么計劃有變
Uh, hold on. What change of plans?
我們帶您回白宮
We're taking you back to the White House.
不  我們得去安德魯斯空軍基地
No, we're going to Andrews.
抱歉  這是總統的直接命令
I'm sorry, this is direct from the president.
這不會像看上去那么困難
This is not gonna be as difficult as it seems.
泰瑞明天一早就跟退伍軍人事務處
Now, Terry's gonna be in touch with Veteran Affairs
那邊接觸  起草修正案
first thing tomorrow to draft an amendment.
如果共和黨在委員會那里給我們阻力
And if the Republicans give us any resistance in committee,
我就開始打電話找人
I'll start making calls.
本輪會議結束之前
No reason why this can't get to the floor
完全可以呈遞國會
before the end of the session.
謝謝你  總統先生
Well, thank you, Mr. President.
謝你自己  你這手玩得漂亮
Thank yourself. You played this well.
你怎么玩的
How did you play it?
那是我們的小秘密了
Well, now, that's our little secret, isn't it?
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
總統先生  我來吧
Uh, Mr. President, I got this.
克萊爾
Oh, Claire.
總統的講話多棒啊
Didn't the president make the most wonderful speech?
是啊
Oh, he certainly did.
多謝你說服總統
And I thank you for convincing the president
在講話中提到西莉婭
to mention Celia in his remarks.
不客氣
Well, it was my pleasure.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
晚安  克萊爾
Good night, Claire.
我們說好的
We had a deal.
我來了
I showed up.
卻利用這個機會給我的競選拆臺
And used that opportunity to undermine the campaign.
你為什么不問我
Why didn't you just ask me?
如果你需要用診所打動桃瑞絲
If you needed the clinic to convince Doris--
你根本不希望我競選  弗蘭西斯
You don't want me to run, Francis.
是的  我不希望  但我們已經達成諒解了
That's right, I don't. But we'd reached an understanding.
我覺得你就是說了些討好我的話
I think you said what you wanted me to hear.
那你誤解我了
Well, then you misread me.
我是在替自己著想  你也一樣
I am looking out for myself. Just like you are.
你為自己著想
And where did that get you,
而不是為我們兩人著想的下場又如何
looking out for yourself instead of looking out for us?
30選區現在沒希望了  你明白的
The 30th is dead now. You know that.
你覺得我會放棄嗎
You think I'm giving up?
怎么  你要跟瓊斯母女競爭嗎
What, you're gonna run against the Joneses?
你會出丑的  克萊爾
You'll make a fool of yourself, Claire.
即便他們支持你  你的勝算都不大
The odds were against you even with their blessing.
我本希望你自己能明白
Now, I hoped you'd reach that conclusion on your own.
但你卻對我撒謊
But instead, you lied to me.
我沒法逼你想通道理
Now, I can't force you to see reason.
但我不允許你成為隱患
But I will not allow you to become dangerous.
我也來一杯
I'll take one.
喝我的吧
Take mine.
克萊爾  聽我說
Claire, look...
我贏下大選后  我們就可以專注于
When I win the general, then we can concentrate
為你在德州贏得參議員席位
on a Senate seat for you in Texas.
你反正也不會想待在眾議院
You don't want to be in the House, anyway.
我們兩人都沒想到會出現希瑟·鄧巴
And neither of us could have predicted a Heather Dunbar,
那么厲害的對手
or how formidable she'd be.
我們現在是在搏命
We are fighting for our lives here.
等你競選  你會希望處于有利地位
And when you run, you wanna do so from a position of strength.
這是個時機問題
It's about timing.
或許是太早了  或許你是對的
Maybe it's too soon. Maybe you're right.
但我得想想
But I need to think.
好吧
Fair enough.
我不能在這兒想
I can't do that here.
回德州嗎
Back in Texas?
我不確定我得想多久
I'm not sure how long I'll need.
需要多久都行
Well, take as long as you want.
我該走了
I should get going.
已經挺晚了  你確定你不想留下過夜嗎
It's late. You sure you don't want to spend the night?
-母親還在等我回去  -好吧
- Well, Mother was expecting me. - All right.
我自己出去  你繼續喝吧
I'll walk myself out. You enjoy your drink.
以前有個男孩
You know, there was a boy
就住在我加夫尼老家一個街區外的地方
that lived down the street from me in Gaffney.
跟我年紀差不多  他叫沃特·萊森
About my age. His name was Walter Wryson.
他以前經常從家里跑出來  來我們家
He used to run away from home all the time and come to our house.
并沒什么充分的緣由
Not for any good reason.
他爸爸不打他  也不愁吃穿
His daddy didn't beat him. He had clothes on his back.
萊森一家比我們有錢多了
The Wrysons had way more money than we did,
但他還是要逃家
but run away he would,
每個月至少一次  直接跑來我們家
at least once a month and come straight to our place.
一般  我母親會打給他母親
Now, usually, my mother would call his mother
然后她就會來接他
and she'd come and fetch him.
但到了第九第十次時
But about the ninth or tenth time this happened,
沃特跑到外面  爬上了我們后院的一棵樹
Walter ran outside, climbed up into a tree in our backyard,
無論如何不肯下來
and wouldn't come down for nothing.
我媽媽跟他媽媽說
Now, my mama said to his mama,
"你讓他在我們這兒待會兒吧
"Why don't you let us keep him for a while,
直到他肯回家了"
until he feels like coming home?"
但是  那小子可真是倔
But man, oh, man, that boy was stubborn.
到了晚上  他還在樹上
Night came, and he was still up there.
不吃不喝  不拉屎
No food, no water... no toilet.
我去睡覺之前
And just before I went to bed,
我往窗外看  聽到了他的哭聲
I looked out my window and I heard him crying.
我說  "沃特  你為什么不下來呢"
And I said, "Walter, why don't you come on down?"
他就搖頭  不肯
And he just shook his head no.
第二天早晨  我醒來  往窗外一看
Well, the next morning, I woke up, I looked out the window
沃特還在樹上
and Walter was still up in that tree.
于是早飯之后  我拿著一盤雞蛋過去
So after breakfast, I walked over with a plate of eggs...
問他是否想來點
and I asked him if he wanted some.
他又搖頭
And again, he just shook his head.
我生氣了
And I got angry.
那小子有個好房子  好家庭
That boy had a good house, a good family,
我求之不得的那種
the sort I would've killed for,
他自己卻不自知
and he didn't even realize it.
于是我去工具棚  拿來把斧子
So I went into the tool shed and I took out an ax.
我對沃特說
And I said to Walter...
"你想知道住在我家究竟是什么感覺嗎"
"You want to know what it's really like to live at my house?"
我一頓狂砍那棵樹
And I gave that tree a good whack.
沃特大喊  但我沒停手
And Walter cried out, but I kept on.
你從沒聽過
I mean, you've never heard
我砍樹時  沃特發出的
screams like the one coming from Walter
那樣的尖叫
as I chopped at that tree.
他都尿褲子了
He pissed his pants,
淋了下來
and it came raining down on the ground,
但我毫不在乎
but I didn't pay it no mind.
我還繼續砍
I just kept whacking away.
于是
Well...
沒過多久沃特就下來了
it didn't take long before Walter was on the ground
跑回了自己家
and running back to his house.
瞧  他不過就是需要點動力
You see, all he needed was a little motivation.
所以我可以給克萊爾時間
So I'll give Claire some time.
但為了她好
But for her sake,
希望她能在我拿出斧子之前
I hope she comes out of her tree
就從她的樹上下來
before I have to bring out my ax.
他要我等著競選參議員
He wants me to hold off for Senate.
我告訴他我會考慮的
I told him I would think about it.
-那么結束了嗎  -不  沒結束
- So it's over? - Oh, no, it's not over.
他在全國電視上表示支持西莉婭
He endorsed Celia on national television.
別去想30選區了
Forget the 30th.
我們得往大想  就在本輪
We need to think bigger. This cycle.
那我們得好好談談我的酬金問題了
Then we need to talk seriously about my compensation.
-接通了嗎  -是  先生
- He on? - Yes, sir.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
我這就給您接  先生
I'll connect you now, sir.
佩特羅夫總統  您現在在跟總統通話了
President Petrov, you are now on with the president.
晚上好  總統先生
Good evening, Mr. President.
早上好  總統先生
Good morning, Mr. President.
你的講話很棒
Your speech was good.
或許有點太...
Perhaps, a bit too...
樂觀了
optimistic, hmm?
我說的關于俄羅斯的話都是真心的
I meant what I said about Russia.
那只是空談  沒多大意義
It's just words. They mean very little.
我愿意用實際行動支持我的言論
I'm willing to back them up with action.
首先  我們該談談救市計劃
First, we should talk about a bailout.
我愿意跟國際貨幣基金組織合作  幫你拿到所需
I'm willing to work with the IMF to get you what you need.
其次  作為示好
And second, as a gesture of good faith,
我們愿把伊戈爾·米爾金還給俄羅斯
we'd like to return Igor Milkin to Russia.
你早該送他回來了
You should've done so already.
我需要你保證他會得到審判
I need your assurances he'll get a trial.
-你在乎伊戈爾·米爾金干嗎  -我不在乎
- What do you care about Igor Milkin? - I don't.
你就是把他送去西伯利亞
You can send him to Siberia
讓他在礦井里死于黑肺病  我都不在乎
and let him die of black lung in a coal mine, for all I care.
但我在乎你的經濟
But I do care about your economy.
你繼續這么殺害受矚目的商人
You keep killing high-profile businessmen
查抄他們的財產
and seizing their assets.
-那樣不...  -你是說叛徒吧
- That's no-- - You mean, traitors?
聽著  我知道他們在密謀造反
Look, I am aware that they were plotting a coup,
但那還是不...
but that still doesn't--
是的  因為是你策劃的
Yes, because you orchestrated it.
-什么  -否則米爾金為什么要飛去美國
- Excuse me? - Why else would Milkin fly to America?
這事跟我們完全無關
We had nothing to do with this.
你...在約旦河谷的事上就跟我撒過謊
You... you lied to me about the Jordan Valley,
你在邁克爾·科里根的事上跟我撒了謊
you lied to me about Michael Corrigan.
我不是想要推翻你  維克多
I am not trying to replace you, Viktor.
我是想幫你  但你也得幫我
I'm trying to help you. But you have to help me.
石油減產這樣的威脅不會好使的
These threats of reducing your oil production, it won't work.
你以為抬升能源價格會傷到我們
You think jacking up energy prices is gonna hurt us,
但那只是敲詐
but it's just extortion.
我不會向敲詐低頭的
And I will not respond to extortion.
我可以把你的叛徒送回去
Now, I'll send your traitor back,
但你不能再
but you've got to stop
查抄公司  把人變沒了
seizing companies and making people disappear.
伊戈爾·米爾金比叛徒還糟糕  他是美國的傀儡
Igor Milkin is worse than a traitor. He's an American puppet.
改朝換代  那才是敲詐
Regime change, that's extortion.
是啊  但那是他們自己的行為  你是多慮了
Yes, but they acted on their own. You're being paranoid.
送他回來  別開條件
Send him back. No terms.
你如果不肯談判  我們不會有進展的
We're not going to get anywhere if you're not willing to negotiate.
那...
Well...
我們沒話可說了
then I believe we're finished.
是沒什么可說了  謝謝  總統先生
And I believe you're right. Thank you, Mr. President.
把米爾金安置在安全地點  他哪都不能去
Put Milkin in a secure location. He's not going anywhere.
米爾金先生
Mr. Milkin.
請你跟我來
I need you to come with me.
我們去哪
Where are we going?
羈押設施
A detainment facility.
我不是要被遣返吧
I'm not being deported, am I?
不  我們要處理你的庇護請求
No, we're going to process your asylum request.
克萊爾
Claire?
如果你想抽煙  就抽吧
If you wanna smoke, you should smoke.
我就是想抽一口
I only wanted one drag.
他討厭你以前拿著煙去馬廄
He hated how you used to go down to the stables with your cigarettes.
我不知道他知道這事
I didn't realize he knew.
他那么愛你  你殺人他都不會在乎
He adored you. You got away with murder.
你一直沒睡等著我嗎
Did you wait up for me?
不  是藥的關系
No, it's the medication.
讓我整天都感覺疲憊  然后又整宿睡不著
Keeps me tired all day, and then I'm up all night.
我...看了講話
I... I watched the speech.
你打算怎么辦
What are you gonna do?
很晚了  母親  我們早上再談吧
It's late, Mother. Let's talk in the morning.
對了  耳環真漂亮  我在電視上注意到了
By the way, those earrings are beautiful. I noticed 'em on TV.
是弗蘭西斯母親的耳環
They're Francis' mother's earrings.
-貌似不止一克拉  -兩克拉
- They look like they're over a carat. - Two carats.
她肯定從誰那兒偷來的
No doubt she stole them from someone.
安德伍德一家永遠能讓人吃驚
The Underwoods never cease to amaze.
母親
Mother...
我需要點錢
I'm going to need some money.
給診所嗎  不是...
For the clinic? Isn't--
150萬  給莉安  還額外再需要一點
A million five for LeAnn and some on top of that.
我以為你的競選沒戲了
Well, I thought your campaign was dead.
是的  但我還是需要她為我工作
It is, but I still need her to work for me.
但做什么呢  我可以向我的朋友借錢
But, what for? I mean, I can't ask my friends for money and--
我們的錢
Our money.
你是指我的錢
You mean my money.
別跟我爭
Don't fight me on this.
爸爸會毫不猶豫地給我
Daddy would've done it, no questions asked.
是啊  我沒他那么傻
Yes, well... I'm not as foolish as he was.
那我只能賣掉地產了
Well, I'll just have to sell the estate.
什么
You what?
錢在信托里  但地產是在我名下
The money is in the trust, but the land is in my name.
-你不會敢的  -我在求你幫忙
- You wouldn't dare. - Well, I'm asking for your help.
-如果你不肯  -幫忙
- If you refuse to give it-- - Help?
我生病時你可完全沒幫過我
You didn't lift a finger to help me when I got sick.
你沒告訴我你病了
You didn't tell me you were sick!
因為你已經背棄了我
Because you had turned your back on me!
你是那么讓人失望
Oh, you are such a disappointment.
你不希望我背著你賣掉房子  但我會的
You don't want me to sell this house out from under you, but I will.
我是你母親
I am the mother.
I am the mother!
■
國情咨文講話一般在每年年初一二月份  國會復會后舉行
其性質相當于"政府工作報告"
美國憲法規定  總統需定期向國會匯報國家發展和政府運行的狀況
每年總統會借此機會  回顧總結過去一年或數年的政府工作
同時公布新一年政府的施政綱領
程序上  首先每年年初
眾議院議長要代表國會向總統發出正式邀請  然后白宮接受邀請
發表國情咨文講話當晚  總統及內閣成員會前往國會山
出席講話的還有  最高法院的大法官
參謀長聯席會議主席等三軍統帥  以及國會兩院的議員們
每逢此時  總統和議員們會有機會邀請一些嘉賓一同出席
受邀者往往是總統某項政策的受益者
這樣他們在轉播出鏡時  會提醒觀眾政府在過去一年中的建樹
■
由于美國兩黨斗爭激烈
所以議員們在臺下落座時會根據自己黨派歸屬而分開就座
總統在臺上講到某項政策和議題時  同黨派議員會起立歡呼
而對立黨派的議員們則端坐不動  面無表情
劇中民主黨丟了國會多數席位  所以議長是共和黨人
安德伍德講話時可以看到同黨派的副總統起立鼓掌
而共和黨的議長則沒什么反應
■
由于國情咨文是美國政壇一年一度的盛事
所以第一夫人的著裝也是媒體和觀眾關注的焦點
2016年奧巴馬最后一次國情咨文講話時
第一夫人米歇爾·奧巴馬所穿的黃色禮服  就非常引人注目
奧巴馬的講話還沒結束  這款價格不菲的禮服便在網上被搶購一空